nasscom.in 2019-09-14

# Privacy policy | NASSCOM

The issue of online privacy is extremely crucial for NASSCOM, which is committed to safeguarding the information provided by its members and other visitors logging on to its Web site. As an organization dedicated to creating a secure environment for e-commerce transactions in India, NASSCOM has been actively promoting the concept of privacy and its relevance for organizations with a cyber presence.

Respecting the privacy of its online visitors, while providing top-of-the-line services to customers has remained the core of NASSCOM’s strategy for the Internet. Our Privacy Policy gives visitors a view of the Privacy Practices followed by NASSCOM and assures them of safe passage through the organization’s Web site.

At the same time, NASSCOM would like to make it clear that its site provides links to other Web sites that are governed by their own Privacy Policies and does not take responsibility for the security provided by these sites. Visitors to the NASSCOM site are urged to familiarize themselves with its Privacy Policy as well the policies of the sites with links on [www.nasscom.org](http://www.nasscom.org/ "www.nasscom.org") , that collect personally identifiable information.

When you provide us with your personal data, you are agreeing to the rules and regulations stipulated under our Privacy Policy and are bound by it. If you do not agree to our Policy please do not use the Site.

**The Privacy Policy covers the following areas:**

  * Type of information collected through the Web site
  * Choice/Opt out
  * Use and Disclosure of personal information
  * Security

**Type of information collected through the Web site**

**Personal information**  
Users registering at the NASSCOM site for specific services are requested to provide some personally identifiable information which become the property of NASSCOM and can be shared, disclosed or distributed to third parties only in accordance with the Privacy Policy. **It must be clarified here that registration is not required for visitors to the site who do not require any specific services.**

The services that need registration include the following:

  * participation in events
  * ordering a publication
  * downloading research reports
  * signing up for membership
  * joining our mailing lists
  * subscribing for NASSCOM Newsletters, i.e. NASSCOM Newsline and BPO Newsline
  * posting a query while seeking a service provider

NASSCOM will not sell or rent such personally identifiable information collected. The personally identifiable information is supplied voluntarily for some of the following purposes:

**_Registration Data:_** If you are merely a visitor to our site, NASSCOM does not collect any personal information about you, except to the limited extent through the use of cookies, as described below. If you decide to use certain services offered on the site, you will be asked to register on [www.nasscom.org](http://www.nasscom.org/ "www.nasscom.org"). During registration you will be requested to complete a registration form setting out basic online contact information about yourself.

**_Other Optional Information:_** If you wish to subscribe to NASSCOM publications, NASSCOM Newsline or BPO Newsline, you will be required to fill up certain personal information related to your email address, name, country, age, choice of password, etc. However, for any of the other services such as registration for membership, etc. filling up the relevant form is mandatory.

**_Credit Card Information:_** If you purchase NASSCOM publications at the Site or register for an event, you will be required to submit your credit card details, including your name, account number and the expiration date. The information is used for billing purposes and to contact you if there are difficulties in processing your order.

NASSCOM uses a credit card processing company to bill users for goods and services which will not retain, share, store or use personally identifiable information for any secondary purposes.

**_E-mail information:_** When we receive e-mails from you, we may retain the content of any e-mail messages sent to us, as well as details of your e-mail address.

**Use of web-based tracking mechanisms such as Cookies**  
Cookies, which enable us to store small amounts of information contained in your Web site browser, may be used on some areas of our Website. Cookies, that help us track your navigation, enable us to tailor our offerings to your needs. The kind of information that may be stored on a cookie includes registration data so that a user does not need to re-enter the information every time he/she visits a particular area.

The information contained on cookies is masked to ensure your privacy and is readable only by the servers of nasscom.com.

**Third party Websites which are accessible from our Site via links, click-throughs or banner advertising may use Cookies. However, it is important for us to inform you that we have no access or control over such Cookies and do not accept responsibility with regards to them.**

**Choice/opt out**  
NASSCOM gives you the choice regarding the collection and usage of your personally identifiable information. During registration for “joining our mailing list,” we request for contact information in order to send bulletins and for advertising purposes. Again, it is not necessary for you to register in order to access and use our Site. You may therefore choose to opt out of providing such information.

Further, once you are registered at the NASSCOM site, you will have the option at any stage to inform us that you no longer wish to receive future e-mails and you may “unsubscribe.”

**Security**  
Access to your personal account online is password protected. We will not release your account password to any person. In the event that you forget your password, you may generate an on-line request for your password to be sent to you by e-mail at the e-mail address used during registration.

NASSCOM has implemented stringent, internationally acceptable standards of technology and operational security in order to protect personally identifiable information from loss, misuse, alteration or destruction. The data resides behind a firewall, with access restricted to authorized NASSCOM personnel.

NASSCOM cannot be held responsible for any activity in your account which results from your failure to keep your own password secure.

**Contacting the web site**  
For questions regarding the privacy statement, practices of the site, or any other transaction issue, please contact [webmaster@nasscom.in](mailto:webmaster@nasscom.in?subject=PrivacyPolicy).

**Grievances**  
For any grievances under the Information Technology Act 2000, please get in touch with Grievance Officer, Mr. Anirban Mandal at [data-query@nasscom.in](mailto:data-query@nasscom.in).
